hctra.org 2014-06-25

# About HCTRA — Harris County Toll Road Authority

##  **What is HCTRA's confidentiality statement?**

The Harris County Toll Road Authority (HCTRA) maintains the confidentiality of your account information including addresses, driver license numbers, credit card numbers, and banking information. HCTRA maintains its systems, networks, and applications in compliance with the Payment Card Industry (PCI) Data Security Standard (DSS).

## **What are the responsibilities of HCTRA employees?**

HCTRA employees are held to high standards when it comes to protecting confidential information. HCTRA limits access to those employees and contractors who need access to confidential customer information in order to operate and perform HCTRA business. All employees and contractors are required to protect confidential customer information. Those who improperly use or disclose confidential information or fail to report misuse or unauthorized disclosures will be subject to disciplinary action up to and including termination of the employment and other legal action, regardless of whether he or she actually benefited from the disclosed information. A person who distributes or misuses confidential information may be subject to civil and criminal prosecution under the Texas Government Code and other applicable laws.

## **What information does HCTRA collect?**

HCTRA collects information from you when you register on our website, respond to a survey, fill out an online form, complete a customer application, create or update your EZ Account, or speak with one of our representatives. 

When creating an EZ Account, you may be asked to enter your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information, banking information, or driver license number, as appropriate. For security reasons that protect you, we do not allow your name, driver license number, type of account, tax ID, and/or company name to be changed online.

HCTRA is dedicated to maintaining your privacy and the safety of your personal data. By requesting three identifying pieces of information when you first enroll online or apply in person, we can reasonably ensure your privacy and your account's protection.

## How does HCTRA use your information? 

Any information HCTRA collects from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  1. To personalize your experience. Your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs. 

  2. To process transactions. Your information is used to process account transactions and provide verification of identity. 

  3. To send periodic correspondence via mail and e-mail. As an EZ Account holder, it is important for HCTRA to provide you with current information about the toll road; therefore, we reserve the right to occasionally send you information. The physical address, e-mail address, and/or phone number that you provide for contact purposes may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your EZ Account, as well as occasional HCTRA news, updates, related product or service information, etc. Please ensure that your contact information on file remains up-to-date to avoid violations and ensure HCTRA is able to provide you with pertinent information about your account.

## How does HCTRA protect your information? 

While no data transmission over the Internet or other wireless network can be guaranteed to be perfectly safe, HCTRA implements a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you create an account or access your personal information at our EZ TAG Store locations and on our website.

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and organizational processes and procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect from you.

HCTRA uses a secure server for all data transmitted through our website. All sensitive information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our database so that only authorized users may access this information. Your confidential information will be kept on file in order to provide uninterrupted service.

## Does HCTRA use cookies? 

Yes. Cookies are small files that a website or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your web browser (if you allow), that enable the website's or the service provider's systems to recognize your browser and to capture and remember certain information. A cookie cannot read data off your hard drive or read cookie files created by another website.

We use cookies to help us process your requests and save your preferences for future visits. Like most websites, if you turn your cookies feature off some of our services may not function properly. Enabling cookies will not store personal information on your computer such as passwords. If you choose not to enable the cookies feature, you can still make updates to your account by contacting our Customer Service department by phone or by visiting an EZ TAG Store.

## Does HCTRA disclose any information to outside parties? 

HCTRA does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer your personally identifiable information to outside parties. This does not include trusted third parties who agree to keep this information confidential and assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you. In addition, we automatically gather general statistical information about our customers. We use this data in the aggregate to determine how our customers use our services so that we can provide improvements. 

We will only release your information when we believe it is appropriate or are required to by law, to enforce our policies, to protect HCTRA's or others' rights, property, or safety. Additionally, we may provide your information as needed to collection agencies only as it pertains to a debt owed to HCTRA, credit card companies, check processing companies, banks, and our interoperability partners. 

## What does the use of HCTRA's services imply?

By using our services, you consent to the terms and the use of your confidential information in accordance with our privacy policy.

## Will the privacy policy change?

It may occasionally be necessary for HCTRA to amend our privacy policies. We encourage our customers to periodically revisit this page to be informed of how HCTRA is protecting your personal information. 

## How can you contact HCTRA? 

www.hctra.org/about_contact/
